<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Com' Concil' tent' in Camera Guihald' civitat' London, die Veneris vicesimo primo die Junii, anno regni Domini Willielmi Tertii ... an Act of Common Council for Setling the Methods of Calling, Adjourning and Dissolving the Common-Halls, upon the Several Elections of the Mayor, Sheriffs, Chamberlain, and other Officers usually there Chosen.</title>
            <title>Act of Common Council for Setling the Methods of Calling, Adjourning and Dissolving the Common-Halls, upon the Several Elections of the Mayor, Sheriffs, Chamberlain, and Other Officers Usually There Chosen</title>
            <author>City of London (England).</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 8 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A49016</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L2861G</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R39360</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">18370042</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 18370042</idno>
            <idno type="VID">107433</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A49016)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 107433)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1637:48)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Com' Concil' tent' in Camera Guihald' civitat' London, die Veneris vicesimo primo die Junii, anno regni Domini Willielmi Tertii ... an Act of Common Council for Setling the Methods of Calling, Adjourning and Dissolving the Common-Halls, upon the Several Elections of the Mayor, Sheriffs, Chamberlain, and other Officers usually there Chosen.</title>
                  <title>Act of Common Council for Setling the Methods of Calling, Adjourning and Dissolving the Common-Halls, upon the Several Elections of the Mayor, Sheriffs, Chamberlain, and Other Officers Usually There Chosen</title>
                  <author>City of London (England).</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Samuel Roycroft ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Guildhall, London.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>London (England) --  Politics and government.</term>
               <term>London (England) --  History --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>Kayla Ondracek</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>Kayla Ondracek</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="Act_of_Common_Council__City_of_London">
            <pb facs="tcp:107433:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 28 -->
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:107433:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 28 -->
            <head type="illustration">
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>coat of arms of the City of London</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>Com' Concil' tent' in Camera <hi>Guihald'</hi> Civitat' <hi>LONDON,</hi> 
                  <date>die <hi>Veneris</hi> Viceſimo primo die <hi>Junii,</hi> Anno Regni Domini WILLIELMI Tertii, nunc Regis <hi>Angliae, &amp;c.</hi> Septimo:</date> Coram <hi>Thoma Lane</hi> Mil', Major' dictae Civitat'; <hi>Thoma Stampe,</hi> Mil' &amp; Alderman'; <hi>Salathiel Lovell,</hi> Mil', Servien' ad Legem ac Recordat' Civitat' praedict'; <hi>Edwardo Clarke,</hi> Mil'; <hi>Richardo Levit,</hi> Mil'; &amp; <hi>Thoma Abney,</hi> Mil', Alderman'; Necnon major' parte Communiar' dictae Civitat' in eodem Com' Concil' tunc &amp; ibidem Aſſemblat'.</dateline>
            </opener>
            <head>An <hi>ACT</hi> of <hi>Common Council</hi> for Setling the Methods of Calling Adjourning and Diſſolving the Common-Halls, upon the ſeveral Elections of the <hi>Mayor, Sheriffs, Chamberlain,</hi> and other Officers uſually there Choſen.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>HERE AS by reaſon of ſome Diſputes concerning the Right and Power of Cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling and Adjourning of Common-Halls, for Election of <hi>Mayor, Sheriffs, Chamber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lain,</hi> and other Officers and Perſons at ſuch Halls uſually Choſen, ſeveral Diſorders have ariſen amongſt the Citizens of this City, to the great Diſquiet thereof.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:107433:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 29 -->
            <p>Now for the preventing the like Miſchiefs for the future, and that a certain and undoubted Method may be obſerved therein for the time to come, Be it declared by the Right Honourable the <hi>Lord Mayor, Aldermen</hi> and <hi>Commons</hi> in <hi>Common-Council</hi> Aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled, and by the Authority thereof, That the Right of Aſſembling <hi>Common-Halls,</hi> for the Election of the Lord <hi>MAYOR, SHERIFFS,</hi> and other Publick Officers of this City, and the Power to diſſolve the ſame, after ſuch Elections made and finiſhed, and not otherwiſe, is, and of Right ought to be in the <hi>Lord Mayor</hi> of this City for the time being.</p>
            <p>And it is Enacted and Ordained for the future, That if after any <hi>Common-Hall</hi> is aſſembled, for any of the Elections, as aforeſaid, a Poll and Scrutiny, or either of them ſhall be lawfully demanded, or any other Difficulty ſhall ariſe, which may require the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>journment of the ſaid Hall, That then the Right of granting and taking the Poll and Scrutiny, or either of them, and Adjourning the ſaid Hall from time to time, till ſuch Poll and Scrutiny are concluded, and the ſeveral Elections finiſhed, ſhall be in the <hi>Sheriffs</hi> of the ſaid City for the time being, and no other; Any Law, Vſage or Cuſtom to the contrary notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding.</p>
            <p>But if it ſhall at any time happen, That any Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pute or Difference ſhall ariſe at ſuch Elections between the <hi>Sheriffs</hi> for the time being, touching any Matter relating to Adjournments, Polls or Scrutinies, that may impead or hinder the compleating and finiſhing thereof within the Times hereafter for that purpoſe limited and appointed; That then and in ſuch Caſe, all ſuch Differences between them the ſaid <hi>Sheriffs</hi> ſhall be determined by the Right Honourable the <hi>Lord Mayor</hi> for the time being; and ſuch Orders and Directions as his Lordſhip ſhall therein make, ſhall be obſerv'd by the ſaid Sheriffs accordingly; And in default of an im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mediate Compliance with ſuch Orders and Directions, That then it ſhall and may be lawful to and for the ſaid <hi>Lord Mayor</hi> for the time being, to proceed in granting and taking the Poll and Scrutiny, or either
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:107433:2"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 29 -->of them; and in Adjourning the ſaid Hall from time to time till ſuch Poll or Scrutiny are concluded, and the ſeveral Elections finiſhed; in like manner as the ſaid Sheriffs ſhould or might have done, in caſe no ſuch Difference had hapned.</p>
            <p>And it is hereby further Enacted and Ordained, That where any Poll or Scrutiny, or either of them, for determining the Elections of the Officers and Perſons aforeſaid ſhall be granted, that the <hi>Sheriffs</hi> for the time being ſhall finiſh ſuch Poll within Three days next and immediately enſuing the Firſt meeting and aſſembling of the Common-Hall; And that the ſaid <hi>Sheriffs</hi> ſhall and are hereby required to finiſh the Scru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiny, and to make Retorn of ſuch Officers and Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons as ſhall be ſo Choſen within Seven days next and immediately enſuing the finiſhing of ſuch Poll: And in caſe of Difference between the ſaid Sheriffs, as aforeſaid, That then the <hi>Lord Mayor</hi> for the time being, ſhall and is hereby required to finiſh ſuch Poll within Three days next and immediately enſuing ſuch Difference, and to finiſh the Scrutiny, and to make Retorn of ſuch Officers and Perſons as ſhall be ſo Choſen, within Seven days next and immediately enſuing the finiſhing of ſuch Poll, in like manner as the Sheriffs ſhould have done, in caſe no ſuch Diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence, as aforeſaid, had hapned.</p>
            <p>And it is hereby further Enacted and Ordained, That no perſon or perſons that ſhall be hereafter duly Elected and Choſen <hi>Sheriff</hi> or <hi>Sheriffs</hi> for the City of <hi>London</hi> and County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> by the Livery-Men of this City, in Common-Hall aſſembled, ſhall be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged from Serving the ſaid Office, after the <hi>30th</hi> day of <hi>Auguſt</hi> in any year, without the Conſent and Approbation of the <hi>Lord Mayor, Aldermen</hi> and <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons</hi> in <hi>Common Council</hi> aſſembled, firſt had and obtained; Any Law, Vſage or Cuſtom to the contrary hereof in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
            <p>And whereas by a Clauſe in an <hi>ACT</hi> of <hi>Common-Council</hi> made the <hi>6th</hi> day of <hi>June, 1683,</hi> it was a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt other things Enacted, <hi>That an Act made the 21th day of <hi>June,</hi> 1643, Repealing Two former Acts
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:107433:3"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 30 -->of <hi>Common-Council,</hi> whereby the <hi>Court of Aldermen</hi> were to Nominate Two Perſons to the Common-Hall for their Election of a <hi>Chamberlain,</hi> and Four for their Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction of the <hi>Bridge-Maſters,</hi> and the Commoners to Ghooſe out of them and no others, ſhould be Abrogated and Repealed:</hi> Now this <hi>COURT</hi> taking the ſaid ſeveral <hi>Acts</hi> into their Conſideration, do hereby Enact and Ordain, And be it Enacted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame, That the ſaid Clauſe of Repeal in the ſaid <hi>Act,</hi> made the <hi>6th</hi> day of <hi>June, 1683,</hi> and every thing therein contained, relating to or con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning ſuch Repeals, be from henceforth Abrogated and Repealed; and the ſaid Clauſe is hereby Abro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gated and Repealed accordingly: And the ſaid <hi>Act</hi> made the <hi>21th</hi> day of <hi>June, 1643,</hi> (ſo far as concerns the Repeal of the ſaid former <hi>Acts</hi> of <hi>Common-Council</hi>) is hereby Revived, and Declared to be in force and virtue. And the ſaid <hi>Acts</hi> of <hi>Common-Council,</hi> Directing and Enacting ſuch Nomination, as aforeſaid, are hereby declared to be and ſtand Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pealed and Annulled to all intents and purpoſes whatſoever.</p>
            <p>And it is hereby further Declared, Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforeſaid, That for the future the Nomination of all and every Perſon and Perſons for <hi>Chamberlain</hi> and <hi>Bridge-Maſters,</hi> and alſo the Election and Choice of them, ſhall be made by the <hi>Livery of the ſeveral Companies of this City</hi> (lawfully Entituled to have ſuch <hi>Livery,</hi> according to the Laws and Cuſtoms of this City) <hi>in Common Hall aſſembled,</hi> and not otherwiſe; Any Law or Vſage to the contrary thereof notwithſtanding.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Goodfellow.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed by <hi>Samuel Roycroft,</hi> Printer to the Honourable City of <hi>London.</hi> 1695.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:107433:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 30 -->
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
